{
    "id": "3faec58bb50f4f3c9ee76df7b17966de",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She was booked for driving at ................................. 110 miles per hour.",
            "description": "We use over, not above, to talk about ages and speeds.",
            "answers": [
                "above",
                "over",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Although he is in his thirties, he is still ................................... on his parents.",
            "description": "We need an adjective here. Depend is a verb.",
            "answers": [
                "depend",
                "dependent",
                "depending"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You can eat ............................................. in my restaurant whenever you want.",
            "description": "The adverb free means without payment, freely means without restriction.",
            "answers": [
                "free",
                "freely",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Britain has .................................... as the land of law and order.",
            "description": "We need a passive verb here because Britain is not the subject. Something is said about it.",
            "answers": [
                "long known",
                "long been known",
                "long been knowing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He wrote his first book after ..................................... from China.",
            "description": "Instead of writing 'after he returned', we can write 'after returning'.",
            "answers": [
                "returning",
                "he returned",
                "he returning"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "All native ..................................... suffered from the white settlement in America.",
            "description": "We need a plural noun after all.",
            "answers": [
                "tribe",
                "tribes"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Since they are not free on Monday, we will have to find an .......................................... date for the meeting.",
            "description": "Alternative means different.",
            "answers": [
                "alternate",
                "alternative"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We spend ......................................... weekends at our country cottage.",
            "description": "Alternate means every second.",
            "answers": [
                "alternate",
                "alternative"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My feet were sore because my shoes .....................................  badly.",
            "description": "Were fitted is in the passive voice. We need an active verb here because the subject is the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "were fitted",
                "fitted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I had more money so that I .................................... visit all the countries in the world.",
            "description": "We use could to talk about ability. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "should",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "His appearance as well as his strange way of talking ........................................ me suspicious.",
            "description": "When two subjects are connected by as well as, the verb should be singular if the first subject is singular in number.",
            "answers": [
                "make",
                "makes",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The report candidly admits that the state funding in health and education  ....................................... eroded considerably.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the singular expression 'state funding'.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have",
                "was"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}